A Guide to the Widening of Washington Street, 1958-1974
Mary Riley Styles Public Library
Mary Riley Styles Public Library
Widening of Washington Street, 1958-1974
Falls Church History Room, Mary Riley Styles Public Library
Record Group 1-8
1 box
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The files were donated in 2004 by City of Falls Church Clerk’s office.
Biographical/Historical Note
In 1957 the City Council entered into a contract with the Virginia Department of Highways to widen Washington Street (Route 29-211) from East Fairfax Street to the north corporate limits. This was in lieu of making Maple Street a one-way road south and Washington Street one-way north. There was an additional project that continued the widening of Washington Street farther south to Cavalier Lane and Greenway Boulevard and later to Graham Road.
Scope and Content
Most of the files contain correspondence with the property owners and with the State Department of Highways. These concern assessments of the property, rights-of-way, and property lists. There are also blueprints that list the property owners.
Arrangement
Most of the files are correspondence and are arranged chronologically.
Contents List
*Includes blueprints
- 1958 (Box-folder 1-1)
- 1960-1961, Resolution regarding location of telephone lines (Box-folder 1-2)
- January-March 1962 (Box-folder 1-3)
- April-May 1962 (Box-folder 1-4)
- June-August 1962 (Box-folder 1-5)
- September- December 1962 (Box-folder 1-6)
- January-May 1963 (Box-folder 1-7)
- 1963-1967* (Box-folder 1-8)
- 1968-1969 (Box-folder 1-9)
- Letters from Property Owners re: widening of Lee Highway between Cavalier Trail and Graham Road, October 1969 (Box-folder 1-10)
- 1970-1974 (Box-folder 1-11)
- Blueprints of South Washington Street (Maple Avenue to Popular Drive), 1969 (Box-folder 1-12)